<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Data Walk</string>
    <string name="display_name">iS Data Walk</string>
    <string name="aboutApp">\n\nThis app enables you to record your Velocity, Total Distance and GPS location while walking outdoors and allows you to share that data online. When the app is activated, your GPS coordinates are saved once every 10 seconds and are then shared on the iSENSE web system (isenseproject.org), where they can be viewed publicly. The recording interval can be changed via the menu. In order to allow you to find your contributed data easily, the app asks you to enter your first name and last initial. If you are not comfortable with this information being posted on the web, please refrain from using this application.\n\nInstructions:\n\nIn order to begin recording and sharing data, press and hold the button that says \"Hold to Start.\" This allows data to be recorded and saved (provided that the GPS on your mobile device has a satellite fix). When you are ready to stop recording, press and hold the button that says \"Hold to Stop.\" While data is being recorded, you will not be permitted to exit the app by pressing the Back button. However, pressing the Home button will interrupt the recording. When the app resumes, a dialog box will appear indicating that data recording was halted.</string>
    <string name="HelpText">\n1. Go to isenseproject.org\n\n2. Login or Register for an Account.\n\n3. Click on Projects.\n\n4. Click on Create Project.\n\n5. Enter a name for your project, then click finish. \n\n6. Enter a Description.\n\n7. When formatting the project, the fields should be as follows: Time (ms), Accel-Magnitude (m/s^2), Velocity (m/s), Total Distance (m), Latitude (deg) and Longitude (deg) in that order.\n\n8. Your project\'s QR code is shown near the top left corner of the page and the project number will be listed two lines under the project\'s title.\n\n9. Remember to change the project number in the app to match your project number!\n\nYou may also use the "Create a Project" button in this app to create a new project with the proper fields set up for you.\n</string>
    <string name="recordingInterval">Recording Interval</string>
    <string name="user_name">Username:</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="enableGPS">Enabling GPS satellites is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
    <string name="recording_interval">Recording Interval:</string>
    <string name="project_num">to project #</string>
    <string name="logged_in_as">Logged in As: </string>
    <string name="Upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="classroom">Classroom</string>
    <string name="iSenseQuestion">Would you like to view your data on the iSENSE website?</string>
    <string name="NoGpsMsg">Enabling GPS satellites is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
    <string name="ExitMsg">You exited the app while data was still being recorded.  Data has stopped recording.</string>
    <string name="firstNameLabel"> First Name: </string>
    <string name="lastInitialLabel"> Last Initial: </string>
    <string name="start_prompt">Hold to Start</string>
    <string name="logoDescription">iSense Logo</string>
    <string name="stop_prompt">Recording Data. Hold to Stop</string>
    <string name="timeElapsed">Time Elapsed:   seconds</string>
    <string name="latitude">Latitude: </string>
    <string name="longitude">Longitude: </string>
    <string name="pointsUploaded">Points Uploaded: 0</string>
    <string name="nameWithColon">Name: </string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="not_logged_in">Not Logged In</string>
    <string name="Reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="digits_restriction">
	    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz -_.,01234567879()@
	</string>
    
    <!-- RAJIA'S STRINGS FOR MENU... -->
    <string name="NameChange">Change Name </string>
    <string name="Exp_Num_Title">Select Project</string>
    <string name="About_Title">About</string>
    <string name="Help">\n\nThis app can record data regardless of Internet or Wi-Fi connection. After finished recording data, the points you recorded will remain saved. Later, if you have internet connection, you can click on upload (a menu option located at the top of the app). This will show you the session name and time that your data was recorded. Clicking on the upload button will publish that information to iSENSE.\n\n </string>
    <string name="menu_reset">Reset Settings</string>
    <string name="gps_icon">GPS Icon</string>
    <string name="ten_seconds">10 seconds</string>
    <string name="john_smith">John S.</string>
    <string name="mobile_user">Mobile U.</string>
    <string name="menu_reset_condensed">Reset</string>
    <string name="velocity">Velocity:</string>
    <string name="distance">Distance:</string>

</resources>