<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Car Ramp Physics V2</string>
    
    <string name="promptForName">Please enter your name</string>
    
    <string name="experiments_no_items">No experiments were found.</string>
    
    <string name="about_app">
        To begin recording data, press and hold the \"Hold to Start\" button. Acceleration data 
		along the Y axis will be recorded continuously for 10 seconds, and then recording will 
		stop automatically. At that time, you will have the option to share the data on the 
		iSENSE website (isenseproject.org) where they can be viewed publicly, or you may simply 
		throw the data away. If you choose to upload the data set, you may immediately view 
		a graph of the data live on the iSENSE website.\n\nTo
		
		make it easy for you to find your contributed data, this app prompts you to enter your 
		first name and last initial. If you are not comfortable with your first name, last initial,
		rough location (specifies city/town at most), and acceleration data being posted on the 
		web, please refrain from using this application.\n\nWhile
		
		recording data, you will not be permitted to exit the app by pressing the 
		Back button. However, pressing the Home button will stop recording. When the app 
		resumes, a dialog box will appear indicating that data recording was halted.\n
    </string>
    
    <string name="updates">Please carefully review the following agreement for this version of this app:</string>
	<string name="about_title">About</string>
	<string name="login_title">Login</string>
	<string name="logged_in_as">Logged In As:</string>
	<string name="recordSettings">Record Settings</string>
	<string name="X">X</string>
	<string name="Y">Y</string>
	<string name="Z">Z</string>
	<string name="mag">Magnitude</string>
	<string name="done">Done</string>
	<string name="upload_or_trash">Upload Data or Throw It Away</string>
	<string name="chooseExperimentTitle">Experiment Settings</string>
	<string name="no_qr">No QR Scanner</string>
	<string name="first_name">First Name: </string>
	<string name="record_length">Set Recording Length</string>
	<string name="upload">Upload</string>
	<string name="digits_restriction">
	    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz -_.,01234567879()@
	</string>
	<string name="changename">Change Name</string>
    
</resources>