<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Data Collector</string>
    <string name="prompt">Would you like to try uploading any of the following?</string>
    <string name="syncTime">
        Synchronizing time is useful when using multiple devices to record data at the
	    same time.  By default, many Android devices\' clocks will not match one
	    another\'s, thus making recording data at similar times difficult.  However,
	    you have a choice to fix this issue by setting a device as a \"host\".
	    This can be done by hitting the \"Send\" button.  Upon hitting \"Send\", 
	    the time from that particular Android device will be broadcasted as a \"timeframe\"
	    that all other phones in the local network can receive.  However, in order for
	    a phone to receive a broadcasted time, that phone must be currently in 
	    receive-mode, which can be done by hitting \"Receive\".  In other words, if
	    you intend on receiving a host\'s time, you must be in receive-mode before the
	    host hits \"Send\". (By default, \"Send\" will also receive the time that you have 
	    broadcasted, should you be the host).  After pressing either \"Send\" or 
	    \"Receive\", a dialog box will tell you the time that has been received from
	    the host, along with the millisecond offset between
	    the received time and your Android device\'s actual clock.  If you do choose 
	    to synchronize time, recording data will now work off of the host\'s timeframe.
	    This now allows for simultaneous data recording across multiple devices at the 
	    same time.  Please note: synchronizing time will only work if all the Android
	    devices are connected to the same WiFi network.  Mobile plans (e.g. 3G or 4G)
	    generally will not allow for synchronizing time.  Also, synchronizing time may not be
	    allowed on some WiFi networks, but it generally works on small, password-secured 
	    WiFi networks.  Should you want to revert to your phone\'s local timestamp, you
	    can use the \"Reset\" button.</string>
    <string name="stopString">STOP\n(Press and Hold)</string>
    <string name="iSENSELogo">iSENSE Logo</string>
    <string name="picAndVidCount">Pictures/Videos For This Data Set: \0</string>
    <string name="takePic">Take Picture</string>
    <string name="takeVid">Take Video"</string>
    <string name="instructions"><u>Instructions:</u></string>
    <string name="send">Send</string>
    <string name="receive">Receive</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="media_desc">Select one of the following options:</string>
    <string name="username">Username:&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="password">Password:&#160;&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="gpsString">Enabling GPS satellite communication is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
    <string name="force_stop">
        You have pressed the power button on your device while data was recording.  To our dismay, this causes sensors
        such as the accelerometer to stop collecting data.  Therefore, we have stopped the data collection process for
        you and will allow you to upload your data up to the point before the power button was pressed.
    </string>
    <string name="description_hint">Enter Description Here&#8230;</string>
    <string name="description_prompt">
        Enter a data set description (or leave blank if you\'d like an automatically generated description) and press
        \"Save\" to save your data set.  Otherwise, you may throw away your recently recorded data set by pressing
       	\"Delete\".
        </string>
    <string name="done">Done</string>
    <string name="timeFailed">Failed to synchronize time.  You may try again.</string>
    <string name="retry">Try Again</string>
    <string name="sample_interval">Sample Interval (ms)</string>
    <string name="sample_default">Default Value = 50 ms</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="guide_text">
        This is a guide designed to help explain to you how to use our iSENSE Data 
	    Collector application.
	    
	    \n\nYou may notice the two buttons at the bottom of this screen labeled
		\"Automatic\" and \"Manual\".  Let\'s first talk about the Automatic portion
		of this application.
		
		\n\n--------
	      
		\n\n<b>AUTOMATIC ENTRY:</b>
		
		\n\nAutomatic is the subapplication you will use should you want to record data
		using the sensors built into your Android device.  Here, you can record a set
		amount of data with a specified sample interval and specified recording time.
		
		\n\nThe layout presented here is a simplistic 3-step button layout with 3 menu
		options.  Let\'s first dicuss the 3 menu items.
		
		\n\n<i>Login</i>: Since this application uploads data to the iSENSE website, you
		must have an account on iSENSE to do so.  This menu option allows you to login
		to your account.  Your login credentials will be encrypted and stored on your
		device so that you should not have to login again once you do so once.
		
		\n\n<i>Media</i>: Here, you may takes pictures or videos.  Videos are not currently
		supported by the iSENSE website, so these are simply saved to your SD card.
		However, pictures taken will be associated with the next data set you record.  The
		first picture you take will be associated with your data set,
		and remaining pictures will be associated with the project this data set is
		being uploaded to.  All pictures are also saved to your SD card.  Once you finish
		recording a data set, the array of media is cleared so you can take more pictures
		to associate with the next data set you record.
		
		\n\n<i>Sync Time</i>: This menu option is slightly more intricate, so we have
		included an explanation there as to how it works.  Essentially, \"synchronizing 
		time\" in this application will allow multiple devices on the same network to
		record data using a host device\'s exact clock time.
		
		\n\nNow that you understand the menu options available to you, let\'s begin with
		a typical usage of this application.  As the 3 buttons on this layout indicate,
		using this subapplication is a simple 3-step process.
		
		\n\n<i>Step 1</i>: The first step is to set up your data set to record data for.
		Selecting this button will pop up a dialog that provides you multiple text fields,
		check boxes, and buttons.  First, you should enter your data set name, or the name
		of the data set you would like to record.  Next is the sample interval, or the
		rate in milliseconds that data will be collected at.  For example, a sample interval
		of 50 means you\'ll be recording 20 points per second.  The fastest rate you\'re
		allowed to record data at is 50 milliseconds since this is the fastest, tested,
		consistent rate at which good, non-repetitive data can be collected at.  The last
		text field in this dialog is the test length, or the time in seconds that you
		want to be recording data for.  By default, we set up the test length to be 600
		seconds, or 10 minutes.  Below this text field is a checkbox to remember your
		sample interval and test length.  By checking this off, the next time you setup
		a data set, your values you enter into these text fields will be remembered.
		However, since these two text fields supply default values, you do are not
		required to enter anything here.  Your data set name on the other hand is required
		and will always save and carry over to your next data set recording, unless you
		change it.  Now it\'s time to select an project (or not).  By selecting the
		\"Select Project\" button, you will be presented yet another dialog that
		prompts you to either enter the ID of the project on iSENSE that you would like
		to upload to, browse a list of project and select one, or scan an project\'s
		QR code.  Once you are satisfied with your selection and select \"OK\", a list
		of the data fields and associated sensors required to record such data is presented
		in another dialog.  Here, based off of common devices running the version of
		Android your device is running, we will make a prediction as to which types of sensor data
		are compatible with the sensors in your device.  You may select which sensory data
		you would like to record here as well.  When finished with this step, you
		will be brought back to the Step 1 dialog again.  Should you be unsure of which
		project you\'d like to upload to yet, or if you don\'t have internet
		connectivity to find your project or select compatible fields, you may
		select the checkbox to select an project later.  Once everything is set up here,
		you are complete with Step 1, and you will see the Step 2 button become enabled.
		
		\n\n<i>Step 2</i>: Unlike the other buttons in this application, you must press
		and hold this button to activate it.  Once you do so, portions of the application
		will turn green, the Step 1, 2, and 3 buttons will disappear, and you will be 
		presented with a slightly different layout.  The Step 2 button becomes a button
		that you must press and hold to stop recording data.  Above it is a text field
		that will read off your setup information (such as your data set name and sample
		interval).  The text field below this button indicates time elapsed in seconds,
		along with a data point count.  Now you\'re recording data!  The orientation
		of the device will lock in it\'s current position while inside the application.
		However, while recording data, you may now use your device\'s home button to
		leave our application and go do other things on your phone - we\'ll still be
		recording data for you.  You may not hit the power button on your device though,
		since this pauses all Android sensors and thus we cannot retrieve data.  When
		you are done recording data, you may hold the layout\'s button down that states
		\"STOP (Press and Hold)\".  The layout will return to it\'s original state, and
		you\'ll be presented a dialog that let\'s you enter a description for your data
		set.  You may now either save or delete your data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Step 3</i>: Assuming you\'ve saved your data set, you may either go back
		to Step 1 and keep recording more data sets, or you may upload your data sets
		with Step 3.  This step requires internet connectivity along with being logged
		into the application with your iSENSE account.  The Step 3 button will be
		enabled any time you have data sets to upload, and disabled when there are no
		more data sets saved.  Your data sets will be listed in blocks, similar to the
		blocks in the sensor selection dialog in Step 1.  Each data set \"block\" will
		provide your data set name on top, your project in the lower left (or \"No 
		Proj.\" if you have not selected one for recording), your description in the lower
		right, and a checkmark in the upper right.  Prepended to your data set name is
		also a label indicating whether or not this data set is just data or data with
		an associated picture.  Performing a single tap on this box changes the icon
		in the upper right to a checkmark or an \"X\", indicating whether or not you
		would like to upload this data set when the Upload button on the bottom of the
		dialog is selected.  Pressing and holding a data set pops up a new dialog that
		allows you to rename or delete a data set.  If your data set has no associated
		project, this is where a third option will pop up in this dialog allowing
		you to now select an project.  When ready, you may press the Upload key to
		begin uploading all of your data sets.  Data sets that succeed will be removed
		from this view and will be presented on the iSENSE website.  Data sets that fail
		to upload will remain there for you so you may try to upload it again in the
		future.
		
		\n\nWith that, you have the basic knowledge required to collect Android sensor
		data and upload it to iSENSE!  The Automatic subapplication should now hopefully
		seem clear and easy to use.

		\n\n--------

		\n\n<b>MANUAL ENTRY:</b>
		
		\n\nPerhaps you do not want to record data using Android\'s built-in sensors.
		With the manual subapplication, you will be able to fetch an project\'s fields,
		manually enter data you recorded, and upload the data set to iSENSE.
		
		\n\nThe manual application will first ask you to select an project.  Just
		as in the Automatic subapplication, you can either manually enter your project\'s
		number, browse projects and locate yours, or scan a QR code.  Upon
		selecting an project, the device will list off all of the project\'s data
		fields for you to manually enter data.  Note: time, latitude, and longitude
		will all be automatically filled in for you when you choose to save a data set.
		
		\n\nLet\'s start with the menu options.
		
		\n\n<i>Upload:</i> This is similar to the \"Step 3\" button in the Automatic
		subapplication.  The Upload menu option will list off
		every data set and media captured that you may attempt to upload to iSENSE.
		Any upload failures will remain on this list.  However, you can choose to
		press and hold a data set or picture and delete it from the list permanently.
		Pressing and holding it will also allow you to rename your data set or change
		the data saved within that data set. Performing
		a single tap on these data sets and pictures will toggle the checkmark and \"X\"
		icon in the upper right of the data set or picture, indicating whether or not
		the application should attempt to upload it when you hit Upload.
		
		\n\n<i>Project:</i> This option lets you select a new project to
		enter data into.  Again, once you select an project, the manual
		application will list off the project\'s fields and give you text boxes
		to enter data into.
		
		\n\n<i>Login:</i> An essential step in uploading data to iSENSE is logging in.
		This menu option is the stereotypical dialog that prompts for your username and
		password to the iSENSE website and attempts to log you in.  You will be
		informed if your login information was or cannot be validated.
		
		\n\nYou will notice a few additional features on the main screen.
		Underneath the main iSENSE logo are two text fields that will let you know
		who you are currently logged in as and what project you are currently
		entering data for.  There are also 3 buttons and an additional text box
		right above the list of project fields.
		
		\n\n<i>Save:</i> This button is used to save your data set once you
		enter data into your project\'s fields.  Every time you hit Save, a
		new data set will be saved and added to the list of data to upload with
		the Upload menu option.
		
		\n\n<i>Clear:</i> This button is optional to using this application, but
		it is generally helpful.  Upon saving data, all fields and data set name
		will remain on the main screen.  However, the Clear button will erase all
		of your data fields and clear your data set name, giving you a blank
		list of project fields to again enter data into and save a new data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Data Set Name:</i> This text box is the place for you to enter a
		data set name, which is the name you want associated with your data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Media:</i> This is the button with the camera on it, to the right
		of the data set name text box. With this
		button, you will be able to take pictures and videos that will all save to
		your SD Card.  Since iSENSE supports pictures, these pictures will also be
		uploaded and associated with the same project your next data set saved
		will upload to.
		
		\n\nIf you have chosen a valid project with fields, you will see a
		scrollable list of fields and text boxes for you to begin entering data
		into.  Once all the fields you want
		to fill out are filled in, you may hit Save, and these values will be
		stored as a data set.  If a text field is labeled \"Auto\", you cannot
		modify its value - we will fill in that value for you when you hit Save.
		
		\n\nAll other features and error messages will be self-explanatory
		as they appear in the Manual subapplication.
		
		\n\n--------

		\n\nThank you for choosing to use our Data Collector application.  We hope 
		you enjoy using it in conjunction with the iSENSE experience!
		
		\n\n--------\n\n

	</string>
    <string name="about_text">	    
        Welcome to the iSENSE Data Collector Android Application, developed by 
	    UMass Lowell undergraduates Michael Stowell and Jeremy Poulin of the ECG/iSENSE 
	    team under Fred Martin.

		\n\nThe Engaging Computing Group “develops new technologies to enable 
		learners - youth, teachers, undergraduates, and others - be creative in 
		science, engineering, and computing, and studies how these technologies 
		improve learning.”

		\n\niSENSE exists as a branch off of the ECG, which involves “teachers 
		and kids in inquiry-rich science projects with electronic data collection.” 
		Data collected from iSENSE project may be found on the isenseproject.org
		website.

		\n\nThis Android application is essentially the general data collection 
		Android platform to utilize the iSENSE visualization tools.  With this 
		application, you may simply contribute a data set to an existing iSENSE 
		project.  Android devices host many sensors, including an accelerometer, 
		GPS, temperature sensor, gyroscope, magnetic sensor, pressure sensor, 
		proximity sensor, and more.  These can all be utilized, should your device 
		support them, to record data and visualize it on the iSENSE website.

		\n\nThe purpose of the Data Collector application is to enable people of 
		all ages to take advantage of the hardware sensors Android offers and use 
		them to take real, personalized data and visualize it using a variety of 
		visualization tools offered by the iSENSE website.
		
		\n\nThis application will also enable a user to manually key in data live
		using the manual-entry portion of this app.  All the user needs to know is
		his or her project and login information and he or she is ready to go.

		\n\nIn order to use this application, you must have an account on 
		isenseproject.org.\n\n</string>
    <string name="menu_login">Login</string>
    <string name="menu_media">Media</string>
    <string name="menu_sync">Sync Time</string>
    <string name="menu_upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="menu_project">Project</string>
    <string name="record_length">Test Length (s)</string>
    <string name="record_default">Default Value = 600 s</string>
    <string name="blank_desc"></string>
    <string name="loggedInAs">Logged in as: \0</string>
    <string name="usingProject">Uploading to project #: \0</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="auto">Automatic</string>
    <string name="manual">Manual</string>
    <string name="splashPrompt">Select \"Automatic\" to record sensor data, or select \"Manual\" to manually key in data.</string>
    <string name="qmark">\&#63;</string>
	<string name="enterDataSetName">Enter Data Set Name Here&#8230;</string>
	<string name="data_set_name">Data Set Name</string>
	<string name="queue_alter">What would you like to do with this data set?</string>
	<string name="rename">Rename</string>
	<string name="change_data">Change Data</string>
	<string name="delete">Delete</string>
	<string name="queue_rename">Enter a new name for your data set:</string>
	<string name="digits_restriction">
	    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz -_.,01234567879()@
	</string>
	<string name="numbers_restriction">
	    1234567890.-
	</string>
	<string name="reset">Reset</string>
	<string name="no_thanks">No Thanks</string>
	<string name="can_login_string">
	    You have internet connectivity, but you have not logged into our application yet.  Logging in now will enable you to upload your
	    data.  However, you can still view your data sets without logging in.  Would you like login now?
	</string>
	<string name="need_connectivity_string">
	    You need internet connectivity in order to login and upload data.  Since we cannot find any of your login credentials and there
	    is no internet connectivity, you cannot upload data sets yet.  However, you may still view your data sets.
	</string>
	<string name="select_fields_for">
	    Please select the fields you would like to record for project #
	</string>
	<string name="step1">Step 1: Setup Your Data Set</string>
	<string name="step2">Step 2: Record a Data Set (Hold Down)</string>
	<string name="step3">Step 3: Upload Data Sets</string>
	<string name="select_proj">Select Project</string>
	<string name="select_later">I\'ll select one later</string>
	<string name="remember_setup">Remember my Sample Interval and Test Length</string>
	
</resources>