<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Data Collector</string>
    <string name="experiments_no_items">No experiments were found.</string>
    <string name="prompt">Would you like to retry uploading any of the following?</string>
	
	<string name="syncTime">
	    Synchronizing time is useful when using multiple devices on a ride at the
	    same time.  By default, many Android devices\' clocks will not match one
	    another\'s, thus making recording data at similar times difficult.  However,
	    you have a choice to fix this issue by setting a device as a \"host\".
	    This can be done by hitting the \"Send\" button.  Upon hitting \"Send\", 
	    the time from that particular Android device will be broadcasted as a timeframe
	    that all other phones in the local network can receive.  However, in order for
	    a phone to receive a broadcasted time, that phone must be currently in 
	    receive-mode, which can be done by hitting \"Receive\".  In other words, if
	    you intend on receiving a host\'s time, you must be in receive-mode before the
	    host hits \"Send\". (By default, \"Send\" will also receive the time that you have 
	    broadcasted, should you be the host).  After pressing either \"Send\" or 
	    \"Receive\", a dialog box will tell you the time that has been received from
	    the host, along with the millisecond offset between 
	    the received time and your Android device\'s actual clock.  If you do choose 
	    to synchronize time, recording data will now use the received time as a label 
	    for data points, rather than using your local time.  This now allows 
	    simultaneous data recording across multiple devices on the same ride at the 
	    same time.  Please note: synchronizing time will only work if all the Android
	    devices are connected to the same WiFi network.  Mobile plans (e.g. 3G or 4G)
	    generally will not allow for synchronizing time.  Also, synchronizing time may not be
	    allowed on some WiFi networks, but it generally works on small, password-secured 
	    WiFi networks.
	</string>
	
	<string name="search">Search</string>
	<string name="startString">START\n(Press and Hold)</string>
	<string name="stopString">STOP\n(Press and Hold)</string>
	<string name="notLoggedIn">Username: NOT LOGGED IN</string>
	<string name="session">Session Name: NOT SET</string>
	<string name="iSENSELogo">iSENSE Logo</string>
	<string name="picAndVidCount">Pictures/Videos For This Session: \0</string>
	<string name="menuDirections">Use Menu to Access Configurations</string>
	<string name="timeElapsed">Time Elapsed: 0:00</string>
	<string name="sessionName">Session Name: </string>
	<string name="experimentNum">Experiment #: </string>
	<string name="browse">  Browse&#8230;  </string>
	<string name="takePic">Take Picture</string>
	<string name="takeVid">Take Video"</string>
	<string name="instructions"><u>Instructions:</u></string>
	<string name="send">Send</string>
	<string name="receive">Receive</string>
	<string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
	<string name="okay">Okay</string>
	<string name="back">Back</string>
	<string name="upload">Upload</string>
	<string name="media_desc">Select one of the following options:</string>
	<string name="scan_qr">Scan QR Code</string>
    <string name="username">Username:&#160;&#160;</string>
	<string name="password">Password:&#160;&#160;&#160;</string>
	<string name="loading">Loading&#x2026;</string>
	<string name="no_isense">
	    You are either not logged into iSENSE, or you have not provided a valid Experiment ID to upload your data to.
		You will be returned to the main screen, but you may go to Menu -> Upload to upload this data set once you log in
		to iSENSE and provide a valid Experiment ID.  You are permitted to continue recording data; however if
		you choose to do so, you will not be able to upload the previous data set to iSENSE afterwards.
	</string>
	<string name="yes">Yes</string>
	<string name="no">No</string>
	<string name="gpsString">Enabling GPS satellites is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
	<string name="force_stop">You exited the app while data was still being recorded.  Data has stopped recording.</string>
	<string name="description_hint">Enter Description Here&#8230;</string>
	<string name="description_prompt">
	    Enter a session description (or leave blank if you\'d like an automatically generated description).
	</string>
	<string name="visit">Visit</string>
	<string name="qr_prompt">
	    Your device does not have the proper Barcode Scanner application installed
		to use this feature.  However, you may visit the Google Play store to download 
		this application (\"Barcode Scanner\" by the Zxing Team).
	</string>

	<string name="done">Done</string>
	<string name="timeFailed">Failed to synchronize time.  You may try again.</string>
	<string name="retry">Try Again</string>
	<string name="sample_rate">Sample Interval (ms): </string>
	<string name="cont">Continue</string>
	<string name="exit">Exit</string>
	<string name="login">Login</string>
	
	<string name="guide_text">
	    This is a guide designed to help explain to you how to use our iSENSE Data 
	    Collector application.

		\n\nYou may have already noticed the initial splash screen (the previous 
		window you were viewing before coming here).  This screen will allow you 
		to navigate to, in addition to this guide, information regarding what this 
		application is useful for along with the End User License Agreement (EULA).  
		The EULA must be accepted in order to use this application. You can view the 
		accepted status of the EULA by looking for the check-mark next to the EULA 
		prompt: checked means accepted, unchecked means declined.  From here, you may 
		continue into the application itself via the “Continue” button, or exit 
		anytime by using the “Exit” button or hitting the “back” key on your Android device.

		\n\nYou’ll know when you’re in the main application when you see a lot of 
		red - a red iSENSE logo, button colors, borders, and more.  We’ll get more 
		into what this red means later.  The initial screen displays our logo, two 
		textboxes that state your current username and session name, a label for time 
		elapsed, a large button that states “START”, and a prompt informing you to use
		 the menu key to access app configurations.

		\n\nLet’s start with the in-app menu, and namely, the username.  If you navigate to 
		our in-app menu, you’ll see 5 options.  These include “Setup”, “Login”, “Upload”, 
		“Sync Time”, and “Media”.  By selecting Login, you’ll be shown a dialog box that 
		prompts you for a username and password.  You do have an iSENSE account, right?  
		Here’s the place to enter those credentials.  If you do not have an iSENSE account, 
		visit our website, isenseproject.org, and create an account through the login-screen.  
		If your credentials are validated, our application will log you in and be allowed 
		to post data/media to the iSENSE website as your account.

		\n\nThe menu’s “Media” option is great for those who want to take pictures and/or 
		videos to upload to their iSENSE session.  The layout is relatively simple - you 
		may take a picture, a video, go back, and view the amount of media taken/recorded 
		for the current session.  These pictures and videos will be saved to your SD Card, 
		and the pictures only (iSENSE does not currently support videos) will be uploaded 
		and appended to your session on iSENSE after you record data.

		\n\nAnother particularly useful menu option is “Sync Time”.  Clocks between multiple
		Android devices will all vary, at least by a few seconds.  This makes simultaneous
		data recording relatively difficult.  As a result, we have implemented our 
		“Sync Time” feature for you.  Selecting this feature will bring you to a whole 
		new yellow-themed layout which will further explain how to use this incredibly
		useful feature.

		\n\nBefore recording any data with this application, you must “setup.”  This can be 
		done through the menu or by holding the “START” button prior to setting up the current 
		session.  After experiment data has been loaded, you will see a dialog labeled “Step 
		1: Identify Session”.  Here, you will enter the name you want to give the session you 
		are going to record, the experiment you want to upload the data to, and the interval 
		(in milliseconds) between each recorded data point.  You may enter an experiment 
		number manually, should you know your experiment’s ID number off the top of your head, 
		or you could use one of two additional features.  “Scan QR Code” will allow you to 
		scan the QR Code that was generated on the associated experiment’s homepage and grab 
		its experiment number and sample interval for you.  Of course, you are still welcome 
		to change any of those credentials at any point.  Don’t have a QR Code scanner 
		application?  No problem!  Our application will re-direct to the Google Play Store 
		where you can download the latest version of the recommended QR Code scanning application.  
		“Browse&#8230;” will allow you to scroll through a list of all existing experiments on 
		the iSENSE website and select the one you’d like to use.

		\n\nWhen you’re done setting up we will gather the associated fields from that 
		experiment and display another dialog, labeled “Step 2: Select Fields”,
		where you may see every field that this experiment can accept data for.  
		Each listed item in this dialog box will tell you the name of the field, 
		whether or not your phone is compatible (able to record this type of data), 
		and whether or not you want our application to record that type of data.  If 
		you do not want a particular field recorded, here’s your chance to de-select 
		it.  WARNING:  There is a chance that our application will tell you that your 
		phone is compatible to record particular data fields, but some phone releases 
		do include the sensors included with other devices of the same release.  
		Therefore, we may still not be able to record that type of data, even if you 
		do check off that list item.  Additionally, our application may tell you that 
		you do not have an appropriate sensor to record a field when in fact you do.  
		Again, this is due to a minor inconsistency between devices built on the same 
		Android version, so you may still choose to attempt to record this field if you 
		think you have the appropriate sensors.  There is no harm in checking/un-checking 
		fields to record.  If you attempt to record a field you cannot, iSENSE will fill 
		each data point with a “0” by default.  In other words, our application should 
		not melt, explode, die, or force close should you attempt to record an 
		incompatible field.  Note the keyword “should”.

		\n\nIf Step 2 doesn’t bring you back to Step 1 to choose another experiment 
		(which will only occur if you chose a broken, non-existent, or absolutely 
		incompatible experiment), then you will find yourself back on the main screen.  
		What now?  You may begin recording data!  Press and hold the “START” button, 
		and your device will vibrate, beep, and turn green.  While the application is 
		green, it means that data is currently being recorded.  Additionally, the 
		“Time Elapsed” label will begin incrementing, showing you how much time has 
		passed since you’ve begun to record data.  That means that while the application 
		is red, data is not recording.  You may stop recording data at any time you’d 
		like by holding down the same button you pressed to begin recording (which 
		will now be labeled “STOP”).

		\n\nYou are at this point brought to the last step, Step 3, where you may 
		enter a description for the session you are about to upload your data and 
		media to.  As stated by the prompt in this dialog, this step is optional.  
		You may choose to leave the description blank and upload (in which the session 
		description will become “Automated Submission Through Android Data Collector App”), 
		or you may choose to describe the data you had just recorded.

		\n\nAfter hitting upload, our application performs magic, and, should no 
		error messages pop-up, presto!  Your session data and media will now be hosted 
		live on the iSENSE website under the experiment you chose to upload data to.

		\n\nFollowing the upload (or even if you cancel the upload), you will be displayed 
		a summary of the data you have recorded, including the elapsed time, the amount 
		of data points recorded, the end date and time, and the name of the .csv file 
		that has been saved to your SD Card that includes all of your data.

		\n\nThat is our application in a nutshell!  However, there are still many other 
		features and errors that you may encounter.

		\n\nWhen you initially reach the home screen, a dialog box may pop-up telling you 
		to enable GPS satellites.  This is required if you would like to allow our 
		application to record Latitude and Longitude data (otherwise, you may close this dialog).

		\n\nIn order to upload data to iSENSE, you must have both an internet connection 
		(via WiFi or mobile connectivity [e.g. 3G or 4G]) and you must be logged in.  
		If neither of these cases are satisfied, an error message will tell you to 
		check internet connectivity and to remember to login.  After both of these 
		issues are resolved on your behalf, you may access the “Upload” feature from 
		the in-app menu to attempt to upload that data set and media again.  WARNING: 
		If you record another data set before uploading the previous one, the previous 
		data set WILL be lost.  

		\n\nMiscommunications with the iSENSE server may happen and cause your data/media 
		to fail to upload.  Don’t worry though - we have already stored a file in your 
		SD Card, called uploadqueue.ser (DO NOT TOUCH, unless you want to potentially 
		break this feature), that will store all of your failed-to-upload data.  
		Upon finally receiving a successful upload, should there be any existing 
		failure-data, a new window will display a list of all failed uploads from 
		the past that you may now try to upload yet again.  Once all of them have been 
		uploaded, this list will no longer appear.

		\n\nCRITICAL: Permission to write to the SD Card is absolutely crucial to this 
		application.  Be sure to enable us to do so.  Otherwise, we may not save any 
		of your pictures, videos, or data on the SD Card, we will be unable to upload 
		any pictures to your session, and you will disable the feature that allows you 
		to re-try uploading previously failed-to-upload sessions.

		\n\nOther features of this application should be self-explanatory as they happen.  
		However, if you have any questions or comments regarding this application, our 
		contact info may be found in the EULA (so be sure to read it!)

		\n\nThank you for choosing to use our application - we hope you enjoy it!
	    
	</string>
	<string name="accept_eula">I have read and accept the EULA.</string>
	
	<string name="about_text">
	    Welcome to the iSENSE Data Collector Android Application, developed by 
	    UMass Lowell undergraduates Jeremy Poulin and Michael Stowell of the ECG/iSENSE 
	    team under Fred Martin.

		\n\nThe Engaging Computing Group “develops new technologies to enable 
		learners - youth, teachers, undergraduates, and others - be creative in 
		science, engineering, and computing, and studies how these technologies 
		improve learning.”

		\n\niSENSE exists as a branch off of the ECG, which involves “teachers 
		and kids in inquiry-rich science projects with electronic data collection.” 
		Data collected from iSENSE experiments may be found on the isenseproject.org 
		website.

		\n\nThis Android application is essentially the general data collection 
		Android platform to utilize the iSENSE visualization tools.  With this 
		application, you may simply contribute session data to an existing iSENSE 
		experiment.  Android devices host many sensors, including an accelerometer, 
		GPS, temperature sensor, gyroscope, magnetic sensor, pressure sensor, 
		proximity sensor, and more.  These can all be utilized, should your device 
		support them, to record data and visualize it on the iSENSE website.

		\n\nThe purpose of the Data Collector application is to enable people of 
		all ages to take advantage of the hardware sensors Android offers and use 
		them to take real, personalized data and visualize it using a variety of 
		visualization tools offered by the iSENSE website.

		\n\nIn order to use this application, you must have an account on 
		isenseproject.org.  You must also accept our End User License Agreement.
	    
	</string>
	
	<string name="menu_login">Login</string>
	<string name="menu_media">Media</string>
	<string name="menu_setup">Setup</string>
	<string name="menu_sync">Sync Time</string>
	<string name="menu_upload">Upload</string>
	<string name="record_length">Test Length (sec):</string>
	
</resources>
