<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Data Collector</string>
    <string name="prompt">Would you like to try uploading any of the following?</string>
    <string name="syncTime">
        Synchronizing time is useful when using multiple devices to record data at the
	    same time.  By default, many Android devices\' clocks will not match one
	    another\'s, thus making recording data at similar times difficult.  However,
	    you have a choice to fix this issue by setting a device as a \"host\".
	    This can be done by hitting the \"Send\" button.  Upon hitting \"Send\", 
	    the time from that particular Android device will be broadcasted as a \"timeframe\"
	    that all other phones in the local network can receive.  However, in order for
	    a phone to receive a broadcasted time, that phone must be currently in 
	    receive-mode, which can be done by hitting \"Receive\".  In other words, if
	    you intend on receiving a host\'s time, you must be in receive-mode before the
	    host hits \"Send\". (By default, \"Send\" will also receive the time that you have 
	    broadcasted, should you be the host).  After pressing either \"Send\" or 
	    \"Receive\", a dialog box will tell you the time that has been received from
	    the host, along with the millisecond offset between
	    the received time and your Android device\'s actual clock.  If you do choose 
	    to synchronize time, recording data will now work off of the host\'s timeframe.
	    This now allows for simultaneous data recording across multiple devices at the 
	    same time.  Please note: synchronizing time will only work if all the Android
	    devices are connected to the same WiFi network.  Mobile plans (e.g. 3G or 4G)
	    generally will not allow for synchronizing time.  Also, synchronizing time may not be
	    allowed on some WiFi networks, but it generally works on small, password-secured 
	    WiFi networks.  Should you want to revert to your phone\'s local timestamp, you
	    can use the \"Reset\" button.</string>
    <string name="startString">START\n(Press and Hold)</string>
    <string name="stopString">STOP\n(Press and Hold)</string>
    <string name="iSENSELogo">iSENSE Logo</string>
    <string name="picAndVidCount">Pictures/Videos For This Session: \0</string>
    <string name="timeElapsed">Time Elapsed: 0:00</string>
    <string name="takePic">Take Picture</string>
    <string name="takeVid">Take Video"</string>
    <string name="instructions"><u>Instructions:</u></string>
    <string name="send">Send</string>
    <string name="receive">Receive</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="media_desc">Select one of the following options:</string>
    <string name="username">Username:&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="password">Password:&#160;&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="no_isense">
        You have not provided a valid Experiment ID to upload your data to.
		You will be returned to the main screen, but you may go to Menu -> Upload to upload this data set 
		once you are logged in to iSENSE and provide a valid Experiment ID. 
	</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="gpsString">Enabling GPS satellite communication is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
    <string name="force_stop">
        You have pressed the power button on your device while data was recording.  To our dismay, this causes sensors
        such as the accelerometer to stop collecting data.  Therefore, we have stopped the data collection process for
        you and will allow you to upload your data up to the point before the power button was pressed.
    </string>
    <string name="description_hint">Enter Description Here&#8230;</string>
    <string name="description_prompt">
        Enter a session description (or leave blank if you\'d like an automatically generated description) and press
        \"Save\" to save your data set.  Otherwise, you may throw away your recently recorded data set by pressing
       	\"Delete\".
        </string>
    <string name="done">Done</string>
    <string name="timeFailed">Failed to synchronize time.  You may try again.</string>
    <string name="retry">Try Again</string>
    <string name="sample_interval">Sample Interval (ms)</string>
    <string name="sample_default">Default Value = 50 ms</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="guide_text">	    
        This is a guide designed to help explain to you how to use our iSENSE Data 
	    Collector application.
	    
	    \n\nYou may notice the two buttons at the bottom of this screen labeled
		\"Automatic\" and \"Manual\".  Let\'s first talk about the Automatic portion
		of this application.
		
		\n\n--------
	      
		\n\n<b>AUTOMATIC ENTRY:</b>
		
		\n\nYou\’ll know when you’re in the automatic application when you see a lot of 
		red: a red iSENSE logo, button colors, borders, and more.  We\’ll get more 
		into what this red means later.  The initial screen displays our logo, three
		textboxes where you can enter a session name, sample interval, and recording length,
		a large button that states “Start”, and a label for time elapsed. 

		\n\nWhere do we begin?  Take a look at the automatic application\'s menu bar.
		There are 5 options, which include \"Experiment\", \"Upload\", \"Login\", \"Media\",
		and \"Sync Time\".  I will talk to you about each of these menu options
		individually.
		
		\n\n<i>Experiment:</i> Selecting an experiment using this menu option is necessary to record
		data.  Without a proper experiment, your data has no where to go on iSENSE!  To
		select an experiment, you may manually enter the experiment\'s number, browse
		experiments and select an experiment from there, or scan the experiment\'s QR code.
		After selecting a valid experiment to upload your data to, you will be brought to
		a Sensor Selection screen where you can see the experiment\'s fields that can be
		recorded by your device.  If your device cannot record any of the experiment\'s
		fields or if the experiment is invalid, you will be brought back to the experiment
		selection dialog where you must choose another experiment to record and upload data
		to.
		
		\n\n<i>Upload:</i> Upload is not the generic \"upload my data\" button.  This feature is
		useful for any data sets that you have recorded that fail to upload to iSENSE.
		After you have finished recording data, you will be prompted to upload the data.
		If the upload succeeds, nothing will show up in the Upload menu option and you
		will be informed that there is no additional data that needs to be uploaded.
		However, if an upload fails for whatever reason, it will be added to this menu
		option which will then allow you to try uploading the data or media again later.
		
		\n\n<i>Login:</i> Another essential step in uploading data to iSENSE is logging in.
		This menu option is the stereotypical dialog that prompts for your username and
		password to the iSENSE website and attempts to log you in.  You will be
		informed if your login information was or cannot be validated.
		
		\n\n<i>Media:</i> Want to associate some pictures with your data?  You can!  With this
		menu option, you will be able to take pictures and videos that will all save to
		your SD Card.  Since iSENSE supports pictures, these pictures will also be
		uploaded with you newly recorded data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Sync Time:</i> This menu option is relatively complex and thus has
		instructions built-in to it upon being clicked.
		
		\n\nNow back to the main screen. There are three text
		boxes that you can fill out prior to recording data.  Only one of them is necessary:
		Session Name.  We will explain which each of these three mean.
		
		\n\n<i>Session Name:</i> This is the place to enter the name you would like to
		associate with the data set you are about to record.  For example, if you were about
		to record the accelerometer data of a roller coaster, you may choose \"Roller 
		Coast Accelerometer Readings\" as a session name.  This field is required before
		recording each data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Interval:</i> Data points are recorded at a particular rate, separated by
		an interval of time between each successive data point.  You can modify this
		interval and record data practically as fast or as slow as you want.  Leaving
		this field blank will default the data recording to the fastest current recording
		rate (currently 50ms).
		
		\n\n<i>Test Length:</i> This feature allows you specify to a time-out feature
		for the data set.  In other words, the number you enter here, in seconds,
		determines how long this app will record data for you for.  It will automatically
		time out once it has reached the value you have entered here in seconds.  If this
		field is left blank, the app will never stop recording data for you, and you
		must manually hold the button to stop it.  Note: if you choose to specify a
		test length, you may still stop the data recording at any point you would like
		manually.
		
		\n\nNow we are all set to record data!  Once an experiment is selected, you are
		logged in, and a session name has been specified (at minimum), you can hold the
		big red \"Start\" button to begin recording data.  The app will turn from red-
		themed to green-themed to indicate that it is currently collecting data.  The
		\"Time Elapsed\" label at the bottom of the screen will increment by 1 second
		for each second that elapses as you can record data.  The \"Start\" button will
		also now become a \"Stop\" button for you to hold once you are done 
		recording data.
		
		\n\nAfter you are finished recording a data set, you will be prompted to enter a
		session description.  This is an optional place to enter more information about
		the data you just recorded.  Following the same roller coaster example, you may
		choose to enter a description such as \"Acceleration data recorded from the 
		Yankee Cannonball at Canobie Lake Park.  Device was kept in pocket throughout
		the duration of the ride.\"  You may also choose to upload your data without
		a session description associated with it.
		
		\n\nOnce you hit upload, our application performs magic, and, should no 
		error messages pop-up, presto!  Your session data and media will now be hosted 
		live on the iSENSE website under the experiment you chose to upload data to.
			
		\n\nFollowing the upload (or even if you cancel the upload), you will be displayed 
		a summary of the data you have recorded, including the elapsed time, the amount 
		of data points recorded, the end date and time, and the name of the .csv file 
		that has been saved to your SD Card that includes all of your data.

		\n\nThat is the automatic portion of the application in a nutshell.
		However, there are still many other features that you may encounter. We will
		discuss some of these.

		\n\nWhen you initially reach the home screen, a dialog box may pop-up telling you 
		to enable GPS satellites.  This is required if you would like to allow our 
		application to record Latitude and Longitude data (otherwise, you may close 
		this dialog).

		\n\nIn order to upload data to iSENSE, you must have both an internet connection 
		(via WiFi or mobile connectivity [e.g. 3G or 4G]) and you must be logged in.  
		If neither of these cases are satisfied, an error message will tell you to 
		check internet connectivity and to remember to login.  After both of these 
		issues are resolved on your behalf, you may access the “Upload” feature from 
		the in-app menu to attempt to upload that data set and media again.

		\n\nMiscommunications with the iSENSE server may occur and cause your data/media 
		to fail to upload.  Don’t worry though - we have already stored a file in your 
		SD Card, called uploadqueue.ser that will store all of your failed-to-upload data.  
		Upon finally receiving a successful upload, should there be any existing 
		failure-data, a new window will display a list of all failed uploads from 
		the past that you may now try to upload yet again.  Once all of these have been 
		uploaded, this list will no longer appear.

		\n\nCRITICAL: Permission to write to the SD Card is absolutely crucial to this 
		application.  Be sure to enable us to do so.  Otherwise, we may not save any 
		of your pictures, videos, or data on the SD Card, we will be unable to upload 
		any pictures to your session, and you will disable the feature that allows you 
		to retry uploading previously failed-to-upload sessions.
		
		\n\nOther features of this application should be self-explanatory as they occur.  

		\n\n--------

		\n\n<b>MANUAL ENTRY:</b>
		
		\n\nPerhaps you do not want to record data using Android\'s built-in sensors.
		With the manual application, you will be able to fetch an experiment\'s fields,
		manually enter data you recorded, and upload the data set to iSENSE.
		
		\n\nThe manual application will first ask you to select an experiment.  Just
		as in the automatic application, you can either manually enter your experiment\'s
		number, browse experiments and locate yours, or scan a QR code.  Upon
		selecting an experiment, the device will list off all of the experiment\'s data
		fields for you to manually enter data.  Note: time, latitude, and longitude
		will all be automatically filled in for you when you choose to save a data set.
		
		\n\nLet\'s start with the menu options.
		
		\n\n<i>Upload:</i> Unlike the automatic application, no data sets are
		automatically uploaded.  Instead, you will be saving data sets in the manual
		application and uploading them all via this menu option.  Upload will list off
		every data set and media captured that you may attempt to upload to iSENSE.
		Any upload-failures will remain on this list.  However, you can choose to
		press and hold a data set or picture and remove it from the list permanently.
		
		\n\n<i>Experiment:</i> This option lets you select a new experiment to
		enter data into.  Again, once you select an experiment, the manual
		application will list off the experiment\'s fields and give you text boxes
		to enter data into.
		
		\n\n<i>Login:</i> An essential step in uploading data to iSENSE is logging in.
		This menu option is the stereotypical dialog that prompts for your username and
		password to the iSENSE website and attempts to log you in.  You will be
		informed if your login information was or cannot be validated.
		
		\n\nYou will notice a few additional features on the main screen.
		Underneath the main iSENSE logo are two text fields that will let you know
		who you are currently logged in as and what experiment you are currently
		entering data for.  There are also 3 buttons and an additional text box
		right above the list of experiment fields.  I will explain these.
		
		\n\n<i>Save:</i> This button is used to save your data set once you
		enter data into your experiment\'s fields.  Every time you hit Save, a
		new data set will be saved and added to the list of data to upload with
		the Upload menu option.
		
		\n\n<i>Clear:</i> This button is optional to using this application, but
		it is generally helpful.  Upon saving data, all fields and session name
		will remain on the main screen.  However, the Clear button will erase all
		of your data fields and clear your session name, giving you a blank
		list of experiment fields to again enter data into and save a new data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Session Name:</i> This text box is the place for you to enter a
		session name, which is the name you want associated with your data set.
		
		\n\n<i>Media:</i> This is the button with the camera on it, to the right
		of the session name text box. With this
		button, you will be able to take pictures and videos that will all save to
		your SD Card.  Since iSENSE supports pictures, these pictures will also be
		uploaded and associated with the next data set you hit Save for.
		
		\n\nIf you have chosen a valid experiment with fields, you will see a
		scrollable list of fields and text boxes for you to begin entering data
		into.  This is where your data is entered.  Once all the fields you want
		to fill out are filled in, you may hit Save, and these values will be
		stored as a data set.  If a text field is labeled \"Auto\", you cannot
		modify its value - we will fill in that value for you when you hit Save.
		
		\n\nAll other features and error messages will be self-explanatory
		as they appear in the application.
		
		\n\n--------

		\n\nThank you for choosing to use our application - we hope you enjoy it!
		
		\n\n--------\n\n

	</string>
    <string name="about_text">	    
        Welcome to the iSENSE Data Collector Android Application, developed by 
	    UMass Lowell undergraduates Jeremy Poulin and Michael Stowell of the ECG/iSENSE 
	    team under Fred Martin.

		\n\nThe Engaging Computing Group “develops new technologies to enable 
		learners - youth, teachers, undergraduates, and others - be creative in 
		science, engineering, and computing, and studies how these technologies 
		improve learning.”

		\n\niSENSE exists as a branch off of the ECG, which involves “teachers 
		and kids in inquiry-rich science projects with electronic data collection.” 
		Data collected from iSENSE experiments may be found on the isenseproject.org 
		website.

		\n\nThis Android application is essentially the general data collection 
		Android platform to utilize the iSENSE visualization tools.  With this 
		application, you may simply contribute session data to an existing iSENSE 
		experiment.  Android devices host many sensors, including an accelerometer, 
		GPS, temperature sensor, gyroscope, magnetic sensor, pressure sensor, 
		proximity sensor, and more.  These can all be utilized, should your device 
		support them, to record data and visualize it on the iSENSE website.

		\n\nThe purpose of the Data Collector application is to enable people of 
		all ages to take advantage of the hardware sensors Android offers and use 
		them to take real, personalized data and visualize it using a variety of 
		visualization tools offered by the iSENSE website.
		
		\n\nThis application will also enable a user to manually key in data live
		using the manual-entry portion of this app.  All the user needs to know is
		his or her experiment and login information and he or she is ready to go.

		\n\nIn order to use this application, you must have an account on 
		isenseproject.org.\n\n</string>
    <string name="menu_login">Login</string>
    <string name="menu_media">Media</string>
    <string name="menu_sync">Sync Time</string>
    <string name="menu_upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="menu_experiment">Experiment</string>
    <string name="record_length">Test Length (s)</string>
    <string name="record_default">Default Value = 600 s</string>
    <string name="blank_desc"></string>
    <string name="loggedInAs">Logged In As: \0</string>
    <string name="usingExperiment">Uploading To Experiment #: \0</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="auto">Automatic</string>
    <string name="manual">Manual</string>
    <string name="splashPrompt">Select \"Automatic\" to record sensor data, or select \"Manual\" to manually key in data.</string>
    <string name="qmark">\&#63;</string>
	<string name="enterSessionName">Enter Session Name Here&#8230;</string>
	<string name="session_name">Session Name</string>
	<string name="required">(required)</string>
	<string name="queue_alter">What would you like to do with this data set?</string>
	<string name="rename">Rename</string>
	<string name="change_data">Change Data</string>
	<string name="delete">Delete</string>
	<string name="queue_rename">Enter a new name for your data set:</string>
	<string name="digits_restriction">
	    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz -_.,01234567879()@
	</string>
	<string name="numbers_restriction">
	    1234567890.-
	</string>
	<string name="reset">Reset</string>
	<string name="no_thanks">No Thanks</string>
	<string name="can_login_string">
	    You have internet connectivity, but you have not logged into our application yet.  Logging in now will enable you to upload your
	    data.  However, you can still view your data sets without logging in.  Would you like login now?
	</string>
	<string name="need_connectivity_string">
	    You need internet connectivity in order to login and upload data.  Since we cannot find any of your login credentials and there
	    is no internet connectivity, you cannot upload data sets yet.  However, you may still view your data sets.
	</string>
	<string name="can_record_string">
	    You need internet connectivity in order to upload data, but you can still record data.  We will save the data sets for you
	    to upload later once you have internet connectivity.
	</string>
	<string name="upload_fail_save_string">
	    Your data failed to upload, but we will save it for you.  You may upload it later by selecting the \"Upload\" option in the
	    menu bar when you have internet connectivity.
	</string>
	<string name="first_time_use_string">
	    Welcome!  Is this your first time using the iSENSE Data Collector application?  If so, read the guide for how to use the two
	    subapplications by clicking on the \"Guide\" tab in the top-right corner on the next screen.  When you are ready, select
	    either the \"Automatic\" or \"Manual\" button to access one of the two subapplications and begin your data collection experience.
	</string>
	<string name="select_fields_for">
	    Please select the fields you would like to record for experiment #
	</string>
	<string name="step1">Step 1: Setup Your Session</string>
	<string name="step2">Step 2: Record a Data Set (Hold Down)</string>
	<string name="step3">Step 3: Upload Data Sets</string>
	<string name="select_exp">Select Experiment</string>
	<string name="select_later">I\'ll select one later</string>
	
</resources>