<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Data Walk</string>
    <string name="get_name">Enter Name\:</string>
    
    <string name="experiments_no_items">No experiments were found.</string>
	
	<string name="aboutApp">This app enables you to record your GPS location continuously while walking outdoors and share the data online. 
	    It has been designed solely for demonstration at the 2nd USA Science and Engineering Festival and will eventually expire.\n\nWhen 
	    the app is activated, your GPS coordinates are recorded once every 10 seconds, and the coordinates are shared on the iSENSE 
	    website (isense.cs.uml.edu), where they can be viewed publicly. To make it easy for you to find your contributed data, the app prompts
	    you to enter your first name and last initial. If you are not comfortable with your first name, last initial, and location being posted 
	    on the web, please refrain from using this application.\n\nTo begin recording and sharing data, press and hold the "Hold to Start" button. 
	    Data will be recorded and uploaded every 10 seconds (provided that the GPS on your mobile device has a satellite fix). When you are ready 
	    to stop recording, press and hold the "Hold to Stop" button. At that time, you will have the option to view the data live on the iSENSE 
	    web site.\n\nWhile recording data, you will not be permitted to exit the app by pressing the Back button. However, pressing the Home 
	    button will stop recording. When the app resumes, a dialog box will appear indicating that data recording was halted. 
	 </string>
	 
	<string name="OK">OK</string>
	<string name="firstNameLabel"> First Name: </string>
	<string name="lastInitialLabel"> Last Initial: </string>
	<string name="startPrompt">Hold to Start</string>
	<string name="logoDescription">iSense Logo</string>
	<string name="stopPrompt">Hold to Stop</string>
	<string name="timeElapsed">Time Elapsed:   seconds</string>
	<string name="noLocation0">Lat: waiting for GPS\nLong: waiting for GPS</string>
	<string name="noLocation1">Lat: waiting for GPS .\nLong: waiting for GPS .</string>
	<string name="noLocation2">Lat: waiting for GPS . .\nLong: waiting for GPS . .</string>
	<string name="noLocation3">Lat: waiting for GPS . . .\nLong: waiting for GPS . . .</string>
	<string name="noLocation4">Lat: waiting for GPS . . . .\nLong: waiting for GPS . . . .</string>
	<string name="pointsUploaded">Points Uploaded: 0</string>

</resources>
