<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Data Collector</string>
    <string name="experiments_no_items">No experiments were found.</string>
    <string name="prompt">Would you like to retry uploading any of the following?</string>
    <string name="updates">Please carefully review the following agreement for this version of this app:</string>
	
	<string name ="eula">This end user license agreement (Agreement) is a legal agreement between you 
		and the developers at iSENSE (Internet System for Networked Sensor Experimentation) and 
		ECG (Engaging Computing Group) of the University of Massachusetts Lowell (the Developer) 
		stating the terms and conditions that govern your use of the Amusement Park Application for 
		the Android device (the Application). Please read this agreement carefully. By purchasing, 
		downloading, installing and/or using the Application, you are indicating that you agree to be 
		bound by and comply with the terms and conditions set forth in this agreement. If you do not agree 
		to these terms and conditions, do not purchase, download, install and/or use the Application.\n
		
		\nDeveloper may enable access to content, information and services (including external and/or 
		online) through the Application (collectively and individually, the Services), and as a condition 
		of your use of the Services, you agree to be bound by and comply with Developer’s Terms of Service 
		and Privacy Policy as communicated by Developer at such time, each of which shall become 
		incorporated herein by reference. You agree that the Privacy Policy and Terms of Service may 
		be updated from time to time, without prior notice, and any such changes shall be effective as 
		soon as posted. If applicable, you should also refer back to the Terms of Service and Privacy 
		Policy on a regular basis so that you remain aware of the most current terms and conditions that 
		apply to you.\n
		
		\n1. LICENSE GRANT. Subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, Developer hereby 
		grants to you a limited, non-transferable, non-sublicensable, non-assignable and revocable 
		license to install and use the Application solely for your own personal, non-commercial use 
		on your present Android device that you own or control. For the avoidance of doubt, the Application 
		is licensed, not sold, to you by Developer pursuant to and subject to the terms and conditions of 
		this Agreement and any other applicable terms and conditions promulgated by any third party (e.g., 
		Android Marketplace, storefront, network, and other operators, etc.), including, without limitation, 
		Google. Developer reserves all rights not expressly granted to you herein. You acknowledge and 
		agree that this Agreement is between you and Developer, and Google and its subsidiaries are not 
		a party to this Agreement and are not responsible for the Application.  In the event of a conflict, 
		the terms and conditions of the present Agreement shall supersede and have priority over the 
		terms and conditions of the Android Marketplace.\n
		
		\n2. RESTRICTIONS. This Agreement does not allow you to use the Application on any Android 
		device that you do not own or control, and you may not distribute or make the Application 
		available over a network where it could be used by multiple devices at the same time. You may 
		not rent, lease, lend, sell, redistribute or sublicense the Application. You may not copy, 
		decompile, reverse engineer, disassemble, attempt to derive the source code of, modify, or 
		create derivative works of the Application, any updates or upgrades, or any part thereof. Any 
		attempt to do so is a violation of the rights of Developer, its affiliates and licensors, as 
		applicable. If you breach this restriction, you may be subject to prosecution and damages. The 
		terms and conditions of the Agreement shall govern any upgrades or updates provided by Developer 
		that replace and/or supplement the original Application, unless such upgrade is accompanied by 
		or references a separate license agreement in which case the terms of that license agreement 
		shall govern.\n
		
		\n3. CONSENT TO USE OF DATA. All data and information collected, used and/or disclosed by Developer 
		and its affiliates in connection with your use of the Application and the Services, which shall 
		include, without limitation, all technical information about your device, system, Application 
		software, peripherals and the use thereof, shall be governed by and subject to the terms and 
		conditions set forth in the Privacy Policy.\n
		
		\n4. PROPRIETARY RIGHTS. Developer, its affiliates and/or their respective licensors own all right, 
		title and interest in and to the Application, including, without limitation, all intellectual and 
		proprietary rights appurtenant thereto, and, except for the limited license granted to you herein, 
		nothing in this Agreement shall be construed to restrict, transfer, convey, encumber, alter, impair 
		or otherwise adversely affect Developer’s, its affiliates and/or their respective licensors’ ownership 
		or proprietary rights therein or any other of Developer’s, its affiliates’ and/or their licensors’ 
		information, processes, methodologies, products, goods, services, or materials, tangible or intangible, 
		in any form and in any medium.\n
		
		\n5. NO WARRANTY. You expressly acknowledge and agree that use of the Application is at your 
		sole risk and that the entire risk as to satisfactory quality, performance, accuracy and 
		effort of the Application is with you. To the maximum extent permitted by applicable law, 
		the Application and any services performed or provided by or in connection with the Application 
		are provided “as is” and “as available”, with all bugs and faults and without warranty of any 
		kind, and Developer, its affiliates and licensors hereby disclaim all warranties and conditions 
		with respect to the Application and any services, either express, implied or statutory, 
		including, without limitation, any implied warranties and/or conditions of merchantability, 
		of satisfactory quality, of fitness for a particular purpose, of accuracy, of quiet enjoyment, 
		of title, and of non-infringement of third party rights. Neither Developer, nor any of its 
		affiliates or licensors warrant that the functions or services contained in, accessed from, 
		performed by, displayed on, linked to/from, or provided by, the Application will meet your 
		requirements, that the operation of the Application or services will be uninterrupted or 
		error-free, or that defects in the Application or services will be corrected. No oral or 
		written information or advice given by Developer, its affiliates or any of their respective 
		authorized representatives shall create a warranty. Should the Application or services prove 
		defective, you assume the entire cost of all necessary servicing, repair or correction. Some 
		jurisdictions do not allow the exclusion of implied warranties or limitations on applicable 
		statutory rights of a consumer, so the above exclusion and limitations may not apply to you.\n
		
		\n6. LIMITATION OF LIABILITY. To the extent not prohibited by law, in no event shall Developer 
		or its affiliates be liable for any loss or damage of any kind, whether direct, indirect, 
		incidental, special, exemplary or consequential, including, without limitation, damages for 
		loss of profits, loss of data, data charges, business interruption or any other commercial 
		damages or losses, arising out of or related to your use or inability to use the Application, 
		however caused, regardless of the theory of liability (contract, tort or otherwise) and even 
		if Developer or its affiliates have been advised of the possibility of such damages.  In no 
		event shall Developer’s liability exceed the price paid for the Application by the user.  
		Developer or its affiliates shall not be liable should (i) the Application or any Update be 
		removed and/or unavailable from the Android Marketplace for any reason, (ii) the Application 
		cease to function as a result of any modifications or updates to the Android software, changes 
		to the firmware of your device or a change of device.\n
		
		\n7. INDEMNIFICATION. You agree to indemnify, defend, and hold Developer, its affiliates and 
		their respective successors and assigns, officers, directors, employees, agents, licensors, 
		representatives, advertisers, service providers, and suppliers harmless against any and all 
		claims, demands, actions, losses, damages, costs and expenses (including reasonable attorneys\' 
		fees), arising out of or relating to your (i) breach or violation of this Agreement, (ii) 
		infringement, misappropriation or any violation of the rights of any other party, (iii) violation 
		or non-compliance with any applicable law, rule or regulation, and (iv) use, alteration 
		or export of the Application (or any component thereof) in violation of this Agreement.\n
		
		\n8. WIRELESS ACCESS CHARGES. Certain Application functions and Services require data access, 
		and the provider of data access for your device may charge you data access fees in 
		connection with your use of the Application. You are solely responsible for any data 
		access or other charges you incur.\n
		
		\n9. CONTINUED USE OR AVAILABILITY. Developer and its affiliates reserve the right to modify, 
		update, supplement, limit, discontinue, remove or disable access to the Application and/or 
		any Services without notice to you and neither Developer, its affiliates nor any of their 
		respective licensors shall be liable to you or any third party should it exercise such rights.\n
		
		\n10. UPDATES AND UPGRADES.  You are only granted the right to the version of the Application 
		as provided when purchased and solely incorporating the features and functionality provided 
		with such version.   You are not granted any rights to any updates, upgrades, future versions, 
		modifications, supplements, and/or additional features and components (including any 
		online or external functionality or Services) of the Application that may subsequently 
		be made available by Developer with the Application or for use with the Application 
		(collectively the Updates).  From time to time, Developer may make available Updates to 
		the Application via software download or other means. Such download may occur automatically 
		without the need for any act on your part, or it may require you to manually download an 
		update or upgrade through the same source from which the Application was originally 
		downloaded. Certain functions of the Application may be modified or discontinued as a 
		result of any such update or upgrade, or may not be available if you have not downloaded 
		all Updates made available by Developer or otherwise.  Developer may, in its sole and 
		absolute discretion, provide you free of charge with Updates to the Application but reserves 
		itself the right to charge additional sums for such Updates the amount of which shall be 
		determined by Developer in its sole and absolute discretion.  Developer does not warrant, 
		represent nor undertake to provide Updates and in no event shall Developer incur any liability 
		for a failure to do so.  Developer may, in its sole and absolute discretion, by means of 
		Updates or otherwise, offer Services as a complement to the Application and reserves itself 
		the right to charge additional sums for same, including a monthly or yearly fee or a fee 
		based on usage.\n
		
		\n11. CHANGES TO THE AGREEMENT. Developer may make changes to this Agreement, at any time 
		and from time to time, by notifying you of the change, including, without limitation, 
		by including notice on the Services or by other electronic means, and a new copy of this 
		Agreement shall be made available on the Services. By using the Application and/or any 
		Services after such changes are made to the Agreement, you signify that you agree to be 
		bound by and comply with such changes and Developer shall treat your use as acceptance of 
		the changed provisions.\n
		
		\n12. TERMINATION. This Agreement is effective until terminated by you or Developer. Your 
		rights under the license granted herein shall terminate automatically without notice from 
		Developer if you fail to comply with any terms or conditions of this Agreement. Upon 
		termination of this Agreement, you shall cease all use of the Application, and destroy 
		all copies, full or partial, thereof.\n
		
		\n13. GOVERNING LAW AND INTERPRETATION. To the extent not prohibited by law, you agree 
		(i) that this Agreement and all disputes, claims, actions, suits or other proceedings 
		arising hereunder shall be governed by, and construed in accordance with, the substantive 
		law of the state of Massachusetts (ii) to irrevocably submit to the sole and exclusive 
		jurisdiction of the courts of Massachusetts, and (iii) to irrevocably consent to the exercise 
		of personal jurisdiction by such courts and waive any right to plead, claim or allege that 
		any of the judicial districts of Massachusetts, USA is an inconvenient forum. No failure or 
		delay by Developer, its affiliates or licensors to exercise any right or enforce any 
		obligation shall impair or be construed as a waiver or ongoing waiver of that or any or 
		other right or power. If any provision of this Agreement is held to be illegal, invalid or 
		unenforceable, the remaining provisions of this Agreement shall be unimpaired and remain in 
		full force and effect. You may not assign your rights under this Agreement without Developer’s 
		prior written permission and any attempt by you to do so shall be void. Any provision of this 
		Agreement which by its nature must survive the termination of this Agreement in order to 
		give effect to its meaning shall survive such termination. You agree that Apple is an 
		intended third party beneficiary of this Agreement and will have the right to enforce this 
		Agreement as a third party beneficiary.\n
		
		\n14. CONTACT INFORMATION. You may contact Developer at:\n
		Engaging Computing Group\n
		Olsen Hall, Room 306\n
		198 Riverside St.\n
		Lowell, MA 01854\n
		http://isenseproject.org\n
		
	</string>
	
	<string name="syncTime">
	    Synchronizing time is useful when using multiple devices on a ride at the
	    same time.  By default, many Android devices\' clocks will not match one
	    another\'s, thus making recording data at similar times difficult.  However,
	    you have a choice to fix this issue by setting a device as a \"host\".
	    This can be done by hitting the \"Send\" button.  Upon hitting \"Send\", 
	    the time from that particular Android device will be broadcasted as a timeframe
	    that all other phones in the local network can receive.  However, in order for
	    a phone to receive a broadcasted time, that phone must be currently in 
	    receive-mode, which can be done by hitting \"Receive\".  In other words, if
	    you intend on receiving a host\'s time, you must be in receive-mode before the
	    host hits \"Send\". (By default, \"Send\" will also receive the time that you have 
	    broadcasted, should you be the host).  After pressing either \"Send\" or 
	    \"Receive\", a dialog box will tell you the time that has been received from
	    the host, along with the millisecond offset between 
	    the received time and your Android device\'s actual clock.  If you do choose 
	    to synchronize time, recording data will now use the received time as a label 
	    for data points, rather than using your local time.  This now allows 
	    simultaneous data recording across multiple devices on the same ride at the 
	    same time.  Please note: synchronizing time will only work if all the Android
	    devices are connected to the same WiFi network.  Mobile plans (e.g. 3G or 4G)
	    generally will not allow for synchronizing time.  Also, synchronizing time may not be
	    allowed on some WiFi networks, but it generally works on small, password-secured 
	    WiFi networks.
	</string>
	
	<string name="search">Search</string>
	<string name="startString">START\n(Press and Hold)</string>
	<string name="stopString">STOP\n(Press and Hold)</string>
	<string name="notLoggedIn">Username: NOT LOGGED IN</string>
	<string name="session">Session Name: NOT SET</string>
	<string name="iSENSELogo">iSENSE Logo</string>
	<string name="picAndVidCount">Pictures/Videos For This Session: \0</string>
	<string name="menuDirections">Use Menu to Access Configurations</string>
	<string name="timeElapsed">Time Elapsed: 0:00</string>
	<string name="sessionName">Session Name: </string>
	<string name="experimentNum">Experiment #: </string>
	<string name="browse">  Browse&#8230;  </string>
	<string name="takePic">Take Picture</string>
	<string name="takeVid">Take Video"</string>
	<string name="instructions"><u>Instructions:</u></string>
	<string name="send">Send</string>
	<string name="receive">Receive</string>
	<string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
	<string name="okay">Okay</string>
	<string name="back">Back</string>
	<string name="upload">Upload</string>
	<string name="media_desc">Select one of the following options:</string>
	<string name="scan_qr">Scan QR Code</string>
    <string name="username">Username:    \0</string>
	<string name="password">Password:    \0</string>
	<string name="loading">Loading&#x2026;</string>
	
</resources>
