<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">iSENSE Uploader</string>
    <string name="display_name">iS Uploader</string>
    <string name="stopString">STOP\n(Press and Hold)</string>
    <string name="iSENSELogo">iSENSE Logo</string>
    <string name="picAndVidCount">Pictures/Videos For This Data Set: \0</string>
    <string name="takePic">Take Picture</string>
    <string name="takeVid">Take Video"</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="media_desc">Select one of the following options:</string>
    <string name="username">Username:&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="password">Password:&#160;&#160;&#160;</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="gpsString">Enabling GPS satellite communication is recommended for this application.  Would you like to enable GPS?</string>
    <string name="force_stop">        You have pressed the power button on your device while data was recording.  To our dismay, this causes sensors
        such as the accelerometer to stop collecting data.  Therefore, we have stopped the data collection process for
        you and will allow you to upload your data up to the point before the power button was pressed.</string>
    <string name="description_hint">Enter Description Here&#8230;</string>
    <string name="description_prompt">        Enter a data set description (or leave blank if you\'d like an automatically generated description) and press
        \"Save\" to save your data set.  Otherwise, you may throw away your recently recorded data set by pressing
       	\"Delete\".</string>
    <string name="retry">Try Again</string>
    <string name="sample_interval">Sample Interval (ms)</string>
    <string name="sample_default">Default Value = 50 ms</string>
    <string name="login">Login</string>
    <string name="about_text">        Welcome to the iSENSE Data Collector Android Application, developed by 
	    UMass Lowell undergraduates Michael Stowell and Jeremy Poulin of the ECG/iSENSE 
	    team under Fred Martin.

		\n\nThe Engaging Computing Group “develops new technologies to enable 
		learners - youth, teachers, undergraduates, and others - be creative in 
		science, engineering, and computing, and studies how these technologies 
		improve learning.”

		\n\niSENSE exists as a branch off of the ECG, which involves “teachers 
		and kids in inquiry-rich science projects with electronic data collection.” 
		Data collected from iSENSE project may be found on the isenseproject.org
		website.

		\n\nThis Android application is essentially the general data collection 
		Android platform to utilize the iSENSE visualization tools.  With this 
		application, you may simply contribute a data set to an existing iSENSE 
		project.  Android devices host many sensors, including an accelerometer, 
		GPS, temperature sensor, gyroscope, magnetic sensor, pressure sensor, 
		proximity sensor, and more.  These can all be utilized, should your device 
		support them, to record data and visualize it on the iSENSE website.

		\n\nThe purpose of the Data Collector application is to enable people of 
		all ages to take advantage of the hardware sensors Android offers and use 
		them to take real, personalized data and visualize it using a variety of 
		visualization tools offered by the iSENSE website.
		
		\n\nThis application will also enable a user to manually key in data live
		using the manual-entry portion of this app.  All the user needs to know is
		his or her project and login information and he or she is ready to go.

		\n\nIn order to use this application, you must have an account on 
		isenseproject.org.\n\n</string>
    <string name="menu_login">Login</string>
    <string name="menu_media">Media</string>
    <string name="menu_sync">Sync Time</string>
    <string name="menu_upload">Upload</string>
    <string name="menu_project">Project</string>
    <string name="record_length">Test Length (s)</string>
    <string name="record_default">Default Value = 600 s</string>
    <string name="blank_desc"></string>
    <string name="loggedInAs">Logged in as: \0</string>
    <string name="usingProject">Uploading to project #: \0</string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="auto">Automatic</string>
    <string name="manual">Manual</string>
    <string name="splashPrompt">Select \"Automatic\" to record sensor data, or select \"Manual\" to manually key in data.</string>
    <string name="qmark">\&#63;</string>
    <string name="enterDataSetName">Enter Data Set Name Here&#8230;</string>
    <string name="data_set_name">Data Set Name</string>
    <string name="queue_alter">What would you like to do with this data set?</string>
    <string name="rename">Rename</string>
    <string name="change_data">Change Data</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="queue_rename">Enter a new name for your data set:</string>
    <string name="digits_restriction">	    ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz -_.,01234567879()@</string>
    <string name="numbers_restriction">	    1234567890.-</string>
    <string name="reset">Reset</string>
    <string name="no_thanks">No Thanks</string>
    <string name="can_login_string">	    You have internet connectivity, but you have not logged into our application yet.  Logging in now will enable you to upload your
	    data.  However, you can still view your data sets without logging in.  Would you like login now?</string>
    <string name="need_connectivity_string">	    You need internet connectivity in order to login and upload data.  Since we cannot find any of your login credentials and there
	    is no internet connectivity, you cannot upload data sets yet.  However, you may still view your data sets.</string>
    <string name="select_fields_for">	    Please select the fields you would like to record for project #</string>
    <string name="step1">Step 1: Setup Your Data Set</string>
    <string name="step2">Step 2: Record a Data Set (Hold Down)</string>
    <string name="step3">Step 3: Upload Data Sets</string>
    <string name="select_proj">Select Project</string>
    <string name="select_later">I\'ll select one later</string>
    <string name="remember_setup">Remember my Sample Interval and Test Length</string>
    
    <string name="welcome_str">Welcome to the iSENSE Uploader.  Select an option below.</string>
    <string name="continue_with_exist">Continue With an Existing iSENSE Project *</string>
	<string name="create_new_proj">Create a New Project *</string>
	<string name="select_proj_later">Select a Project Later</string>
	<string name="star_equals_welcome">* = requires internet connectivity</string>
	<string name="what_to_do">What would you like to do?</string>
	<string name="pre_data_collector_str">Collect Data Using My Device\'s Hardware Sensors</string>
	<string name="pre_manual_entry_str">Manually Enter Data *</string>
    <string name="pre_csv_uploader_str">Upload a .csv File From My Device</string>
    <string name="star_equals_select">* = requires a project first</string>
    
    <string name="field_type">Add Field</string>
    <string-array name="field_type_array">
        <item>Timestamp</item>
        <item>Number</item>
        <item>Text</item>
        <item>Location</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="field_name">field name</string>
    <string name="units">units</string>
    <string name="deg">deg</string>
    <string name="latitude">Latitude</string>
    <string name="longitude">Longitude</string>
    <string name="new_proj_name">New Project Name</string>
    <string name="long_press_field">(long press a field to delete it)</string>
    <string name="how_to_add_field">Select a field type from the drop down menu below to add a new field to your project.</string>
    
</resources>